<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Development on</title><link>/categories/development/</link><description>Recent content in Development on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 12:14:34 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Orchard Structure Classification</title><link>/portfolio/project-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/project-1/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="project-requirements">Project Requirements&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Food security is a large problem faced globally with many factors influencing it such as high population growth, global
warming and poor agricultural systems. As the human population continues to rise at an exponential rate the need for
food security has become a pertinent issue. Agriculturalists have to look to alternative methods to produce larger
amounts of food whilst facing land constraints. This has given rise to the concept of precision agriculture. This is a
practise that assists farmers in making management decisions through abstracting data from technology such as
satellites, drones, robots and sensors. The data collected via the technology allows farmers to monitor their crops more
closely and efficiently.These findings can be used to evaluate yield, soil condition, plant health, fertilizer and
pesticide effect and irrigation. This project serves to analyze the most effective yield that can be produced by
planting patterns. Farmers organize their orchards into different planting patterns to assist with the many aspects of
farm management, such as efficient irrigation and cross-pollination, accessibility for farm equipment and for ease of
harvesting. These structures affect the system management recommendations produced through precision agriculture, and
assist in providing a strong preliminary for detecting individual trees, as well as identifying locations where trees
are missing. There have been many studies conducted over the years to determine the most optimal structure and density
for plants per unit area. There is a vast array of results as certain experiments yield different results and it is
challenging to determine one specific pattern that Is the best, holding all other factors constant. Using precision
farming to detect these patterns in orchards and accurately determine the most suitable structures based on the real
data. The goal of this project was to determine what planting pattern is present from aerial images of an orchard or
plantation and extract key parameters about the orchard.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Artwork Design</title><link>/portfolio/project-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/project-5/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="project-requirements">Project Requirements&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The requirement was to design a TCP client-server program that allows users to send and receive messages and files.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>